Guide to the Olgivanna Lloyd Wright Letters, 1926-1931, to Maude E. Devine
Department of Special Collections
Olgivanna Lloyd Wright Letters, 1926-1931, to Maude E. Devine
Special Collections M0518
Wright, Olgivanna Lloyd.
96 p. (25 letters and 1 postcard)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1989.
Biographical Note
Olgivanna was Wright's third and last wife. Maude E. Devine was the friend who transcribed the manuscript of Wright's autobiography.
Scope and Content
The letters span the period of the bank seizure of Taliesin, Wright's work on The Biltmore Hotel in Phoenix, plans for a resort, San Marcos in the Desert (never built), "Graycliff," a summer house for his old patron, Darwin D. Martin, and other projects. Includes a small snapshot of the Wright's daughter, Iovanna, enclosed with the letter of 9 Jan. 1927.
Access Terms
Devine, Maude E.; Martin, Darwin D.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.; Architecture, Modern--20th century.
Container List
- Dec. 3, 1926from New York. Personal note about Olgivanna's recent daily routine and Mr. Wright's complaints that she is a bad wife., Item 1 (Folder 1)
- n.d.(near same time as previous letter). Still feeling unsettled but Mrs. Devine's;etters help her. Refers to Tussy, nickname for her daughter Iovanna. Remarks on encounter with a friend, Mine Rubloff., Item 2 (Folder 1)
- Dec. 22, 1926from New York. Busy social life. Forgetting our troubles when she sees others' suffering. Remarks on Frank's friend William Norman Guthry, Minister at St. Marks in the Bowery., Item 3 (Folder 1)
- Jan. 4, 1927from New York. Tussy. Sale at gallery coming soon. POst card is a picture of Tussy., Item 4 (Folder 2)
- Jan. 12, 1927from New YOrk. Studying Togi Philosophy. Discussion of losing and rediscovering herself., Item 5 (Folder 2)
- Feb. 7, 1927from New York. She and Frank had been in Washington, D.C.. Mr. Donovan (attorney?) more than understands the injustice being done to us by the last court action. Tussy. Frank working hard., Item 6 (Folder 2)
- Mar. 14, 1927from New York. Working on getting back to Taliesen. Still enjoying New York. Refers to Henry Tell, editor of Deleaneator[sic]. Tussy baptized., Item 7 (Folder 2)
- Apr. 2, 1927from New York. Frank may lose Taliesen. Olgivanna thinks that only because he is a great man he can handle it., Item 8 (Folder 2)
- May 13, 1927from New York. Tussy is walking. Frank to Chicago, last chance to save Taliesen. She plans to take typewriting lessons., Item 9 (Folder 2)
- Jul. 6, 1927from Spring Green, Wisconsin (Taliesen). In Wisconsin at last! Soon to move back into Taliesen. Svetlana has joined them. Frank working on autobiography. Refers to friend Frances., Item 10 (Folder 2)
- Postmarked Jul. 18, 1927from Sring Green, Wisconsin. Frank's salary will be very limited and they will have only half of it after Miriam's pay. You don't mean to say that the terribly treacherous Viola who laughed and betrayed us on the witness stand is woeking for Thayer's..., Item 11 (Folder 2)
- Aug. 31, 1927from Taliesen. Divorce cost them so mush. ASks Maude to come for visit., Item 12 (Folder 2)
- Sept. 26, 1927from Taliesen. Sent Hiroshige Japanese Prints to Maude. Warmth of Taliesen. Svetlana at Hillcrest School, Bauer Dam, Wisc., Item 13 (Folder 2)
- Oct. 9. 1927from Washington, D.C. Hoping that Miriam will get the worst of it., Item 14 (Folder 2)
- Nov. 29, 1927from Taliesen. THere is little chance for Miriam. She has not heard from Frances., Item 15 (Folder 2)
- Dec. 28, 1927from Taliesen. Christmas in Rockford, Ill. where she keeps and apartment. Frank wrote a story Taliesen on the building of it and sending it to Liberty., Item 16 (Folder 2)
- Postmarked Jan. 16, 1928from Roskford, Ill. Will probably leave USA and marry abroad so visa can be granted immediately. Bank of Wisconsin going to sell furniture and all at Taliesen., Item 17 (Folder 3)
- Feb. 1, 1928from Phoenix. Living in a house built be Frank;'s disciple Albert McArthur. Sale at Taliesen postponed., Item 18 (Folder 3)
- Feb. 27, 1928from Phoenix. Bought a Dodge Victory car. Frank paid monthly for help in building hitel in ARizona. Liberty paid $1500 for Taliesen story. Designed covers for Liberty, hoping for contract for 52. Auction at Taliesen postponed. Tussy., Item 19 (Folder 3)
- Oct. 3, 1928from Colorado Springs. Postcard sent on way back to Taliesen., Item 20 (Folder 3)
- Oct. 9, 1928from Taliesen. Frank has to finish plans for San Marcos in the Desert, hotel in Arisona., Item 21 (Folder 3)
- Dec. 12. 1928from Taliesen. Frank finishing plans for hoel. Wil be back in Arizona soon., Item 22 (Folder 3)
- Jan. 4, 1929from Taliesen. Both she and Frank have been sick. Leaving for Arizona at end of month., Item 23 (Folder 4)
- Apr. 29, 1929from Chandler, Arizona. Frank working on plans for hotel which is almost finished. Son Lloyd is helping. Svetlana in school in Shandler. Have a grand piano., Item 24 (Folder 4)
- Dec. 29, 1929from Taliesen. Going to Mexico for two weeks., Item 25 (Folder 4)
- Mar. 29, 1931from Taliesen. My story is out in Boorman (March). They took a long trip to Oregon., Item 26 (Folder 5)